The verdict: The court finds that no civilian lives
判決
ワイルドタイガーが
ヒーローＴＶ内で起こした
were saved as a result of the structural damages
施設物破損について当局は
その行為により救出された市民が
いない事実関係を認める
inflicted by Wild Tiger during the filming of HERO TV.
Therefore,
Apollon Media must pay for all damages to the repairs.
よって賠償金の全額を
アポロンメディアの負担とする
Okay...
はーい
Court adjourned.
これにて閉廷
Hey, why are you getting mad? This is my problem.
なあ なんでお前が怒ってるんだよ
俺の問題だろ？
This is my problem too!
僕の問題でもあるんです
あんな判決
We work as a team,
and that verdict will take points away from both of us.
コンビとしてマイナスポイントですよ
Who cares about points?
ポイントなんて関係ねぇだろう
We're doing it for the sake of the people—
俺らは
あくまで市民のためにだな…
Cut it out!
いい加減にしてください
Since we're a team, I've tried to put up with this,
げっ
コンビ組んでから
ずっと我慢してきたんですけど
but I've had enough of your meddling.
もう うんざりなんです
あなたの おせっかい
Meddling?
おせっかい？
You say you did it to protect the citizens,
市民を守るためとか言って
結局 建物壊しただけですよ
but all you did was destroy buildings.
You weren't helping anybody.
余計な おせっかいじゃないですか
It was just this once.
いやぁ それ今回たまたま…
You're always like this!
いつもですよ！
You even butt into my personal business,
僕のプライベートにも
like if I'm eating properly, and what not.
“ちゃんと飯食ってる？”とか
口つっこんできて
What's the big deal?
そらあ別にいいだろう
It drives me crazy!
なんかペース狂うんです
Anyway, try to understand that some of the things you do
とにかく あなたが“よかれ”と思って
やってることでも
in good faith are causing problems for those around you!
“周りに迷惑かけてる”ってことを
わかってください
うーん
Mr. Barnaby!
ああ！　バーナビーさん
Can I get your autograph?! My kid's a big fan of yours.
サインお願いできますか？
この子が大ファンで
This kid?
この子が？
Oh yeah, happy birthday.
そうだ　おめでとうございます
Huh?
Tomorrow's your birthday, isn't it?
えっ？
明日お誕生日ですよね？
Why, yes.
ああ
あっ？
Someone with your status
バーナビーさんくらいのお方だと
must have an extravagant birthday planned.
さぞゴージャスでエクセレントな
お誕生日を過ごされるんでしょうね
Not really.
いや　特になにも
Here you go.
はい
Wow, I'll treasure it forever!
うわあ　一生の宝物です
Oh!
ああ
Please, let me get that for you.
ああ　いいです いいです
I'm sure it's difficult while carrying your baby.
お子さん抱えて大変でしょ？
あっ
Hey!
あっ ああ！
Umm...
あの…
ああ
What's wrong with that car?!
なんなんだ　あの車！
空気読め！　クソ車！
Stupid car's got terrible timing!
gokigen yo doukashitan darou?
How are you? Is something wrong?
ごきげんよう どうかしたんだろ？
kao wo mireba isshun de wakaru yo
I can tell just by looking at you.
顔を見れば一瞬でわかるよ
senrigan senrigan? messou nai desu
Am I psychic? Of course not.
千里眼千里眼？
めっそうないです
taikutsu GIRL megumaretai no kai
Bored girl, do you want to find happiness?
退屈ガール 恵まれたいのかい
hantei wa shingi no renzoku de
Let's think it through and decide.
判定は審議の連続で
VENUS SUSTAIN
Venus Sustain.
ヴィーナスサステイン
odoru machinami
The city dances.
踊る街並み
PERFECTLY EUPHORIA
Perfectly, Euphoria!
Perfectly Euphoria!
nandemo nai youna kotoba de naitari suru shi
I end up crying over the smallest things.
何でもないような
言葉で泣いたりするし
hora bokutachi nante
Come on, our
ほら 僕達なんて
zentei no nai
temporary passion
juubun tekido ni
lives are
十分適度に
zentei no nai
a temporary passion
DRAMATIC sa
reasonably dramatic.
ドラマチックさ
saikou no wa
the best passion
karuku SUPER STAR
We're almost like super stars!
軽くスーパースター
ORION wo nazoru konna fukai yoru
Looking up at Orion late at night.
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
tsunagaretai hanasaretai
I want to connect. I want to be free.
つながりたい 離されたい
tsumari hanshinhangi acchi kocchi
Basically, I'm not sure and can't decide.
つまり半信半疑あっちこっち
shin mirai wo negau kuuzenzetsugo no
I pray for a new future. The greatest one yet.
新未来を願う 空前絶後の
kotoba ga moshi, moshi tsumugeru nara jikan ga tomaru yo
If I could spin words, time would stop.
言葉がもし もし紡げるなら
時間が止まるよ
koko de owaru hazu ga nai no ni
"There's no way it can end here."
｢ココデオワルハズガナイノニ」
おはようさーん
Morning, people!
Isn't the weather wonderful today?
いやあ 今日もいい天気ですねぇ
Yeah, I guess.
うーん そうね
After looking at those blue skies,
こんな青空見てたら
賠償金なんて
things like having to pay fines seem so trivial, don't you think?
ちっぽけなこと気にしてる場合じゃ
ねぇって気になるねぇ
I don't think so.
それは困るんだけど
まあ いいじゃない いいじゃない
Now, now, take it easy.
ふー
ん？　おい どうした
具合悪いのか？
What's wrong? Are you feeling sick?
No.
違いますよ
Your face just reminded me of what happened yesterday.
あなたの顔を見たら
昨日のことを思い出してしまって
あっ ああ！
ふー
で なんだよ 昨日のことって？
Hey! What happened yesterday?
Never mind. I'm getting sad just thinking about it.
もういいです
悲しくなるだけですから
悲しくなる？　昨日？
Sad? Yesterday?
Someone with your status
さぞゴージャスでエクセレントな
お誕生日を過ごされるんでしょうね
must have an extravagant birthday planned.
Not really.
いや　特になにも
まさか アイツ
Could it be?
A birthday party?
バースデーパーティー？
そう！　みんなでバニーを
祝ってやろうじゃないか
That's right! Let's throw a party for Bunny!
I think that's wonderful!
いいじゃない　素敵
But was pretty boy really that depressed?
でもホントにあのハンサムが
そんなに悲しんでたの？
Yeah. It's the first time I've ever seen him look so sad.
ああ 俺は初めて見たよ
アイツのあんな さびしそうな顔
あれは さびしい誕生日を
祝ってほしいってサインだな
It's a sign that he wants us to celebrate his birthday.
You sure you're not meddling in his personal business?
余計な おせっかいってことないか？
What?
なに？
だって あんなクールな男が
サプライズなんか喜びそうにないぞ
I mean he doesn't seem like the type to enjoy surprises.
わかってねぇな
You just don't understand!
ああいうヤツこそ
サプライズで祝ってやったら
When you surprise people like that with parties,
they get teary, say thank you, and shake your hand.
涙流して“ありがとう”って
握手してくるぞ
私はやめとく
I'll pass.
Huh?
ああ？
別に握手してもらいたくないもん
I'm not interested in shaking his hand.
それに
私たち一応ライバルなわけだし
And besides, we are rivals, you know.
That's true!
確かにそうだな
But Fire Emblem says he's in.
でもファイヤーエンブレムは
やるって言ってくれてるよ
言われてみれば　そうねぇ
Come to think of it, they're right.
Hey!
お おい
What's wrong with you guys?
なんだよ お前ら
誕生日ぐらい 皆でわいわい
祝ってやってもいいんじゃねぇのか？
Aren't birthdays a time for everyone to celebrate?
Wonderful!
素晴らしい！
Truly wonderful! Birthdays are a special day.
実に素晴らしい
誕生日とは特別な日
I believe everyone should celebrate such a happy occasion!
そんな日は皆で祝ってやるのが
ハッピーだと私は思う
Right, Mister Wild?
なあ ワイルドくん
But these guys are not...
いや でもコイツらがさあ
やっぱお祝いしよう
Let's throw a party!
ああ？
Huh?
Well, if the King of Heroes says so, I'll join in.
キング オブ ヒーローが言うなら
したがってやるか
さすがスカイハイ
いいこと言うわ
I like what you say, Sky High.
おい！
ほとんど同じこと言ってたぞ
Hey, he said the same thing that I did!
では諸君！
Now then, everyone!
Let's work together to throw a party for Barnaby!
皆で協力してバーナビーくんを
祝おうではないか！
おう！
All right!
He stole the show...
仕切られた
So? What kind of present are you getting for him?
ねえ　プレゼント何にするの？
ああ？　このサプライズが
プレゼントだけど？
Huh? This surprise party is his present.
ダメでしょ ちゃんと心のこもった
プレゼントを用意しなきゃ
You can't do that.
You need to give him something from the heart.
ええ　え？
じゃ どんなのがいいんだ？
Then what would be good?
You're hopeless. Want me to help you out?
しょうがないなあ
私が考えてあげよっかあ？
Uh... Okay.
おお おっうん
You might look good in this.
お前こういうの似合うんじゃない？
絶対に着たくありません
I don't ever want to wear that.
I see.
あ そう
あっ この中だったら
どれが好きだい？
Which one of these do you like?
帽子は かぶらない主義なんで
I'm not into wearing hats.
Oh yeah...
だなぁ
ああ じゃあ
このエプロンだったら？
Then what about this apron?
なんなんですか
さっきから
What is your problem?!
Well, I'm doing research on everyone.
いやぁ 皆にリサーチしてるんだよ
今 人類は何を
欲しがっているのかって
I want to know what people are into right now.
Why do you want to know that?
何のためにそんな
It doesn't matter! Isn't there anything you want?
いいだろ 別に
何かないのかよ　欲しいもん
I want that.
じゃあ あれ
Huh? You want a TV?
え えっえっえっ？
テレビ欲しいのか？
I meant, that diamond!
じゃなくて あのダイヤですよ
あっ？
The diamond known as the Tears of Hercules
“ヘラクレスの涙”と呼ばれる
ダイヤモンドが
ここ シュテルンビルト中央博物館にて
公開されました
is on display here in the Stern Bild Central Museum.
時価にしておよそ
600万シュテルンドルにも及ぶ
People have been lining up to get a glimpse of this diamond,
このダイヤモンド見たさに
which is roughly valued at six million Stern Dollars.
市民たちが行列をなしています
Well, that's out of the question.
こりゃあ無理だろう
絶対にこれが欲しい
I definitely want this.
よーし　次はこれを盗むぞお
All right, let's steal this next.
またですか　坊っちゃん
Again, master?!
What? Do you have a problem?
なんだよう　文句あんのかよう
これだけあれば
もう充分ではないですか
You have all this.
Don't you have enough?
If there's anything I want, I make it mine!
欲しいと思ったものは
必ず僕のものにするんだよ
I can get anything.
だって何でも手に入るんだもん
As long as I have my wealth, and this power of mine...
僕の財力とこの能力があれば
ふふふふーふふん
お前を呼んだのは他でもない
I called you because
there is a gang of thieves hidden around here.
どうやらこの辺に
窃盗団が潜んでいるらしいんだ
一緒に捕まえないか？
バニー
Shall we catch them together, Bunny?
I guess I have no choice.
しょうがないですねぇ
サンキューな
Thanks!
ええいっ　えっ
Hey! He's the thief! Let's go!
あ！　アイツだ窃盗犯は
行くぞ
うん
Okay.
えっ へっ へっ
待て！
Wait!
ええ へっ へっ へっ
There you are!
見つけたぞ！
Save me, boss!
助けてください　親分
You're the boss of the thieves, aren't you?
お前だな　窃盗犯の親分は
Who are you guys?
貴様ら何者だ？
うははは
We don't give out our names to people like you!
貴様に名乗る名前などない
We're going to catch you, scum!
お前みたいなクズ野郎
とっとと捕まえてやるぜ
そう簡単にできるかな？
Do you think that'll be easy?
What?!
なに？
Put your hands up!
手を挙げな
おおっ
Oh no! We're surrounded.
ヤバい　囲まれた
You've been badmouthing our boss—calling him scum.
うちの親分にひどい事
言ってくれるじゃないか
あ クズ野郎だなんて
What should we do, Bunny?
どうしようバニー？
I don't know.
しょんな事言われても
ふっふっふ
これで終わりだな
It's over.
And you are through!
そしてジ・エンドだ
Save us!
助けてくれぇ
Die!
死ね！
Happy birthday!
ハッピーバースデー
Okay, cut!
はーいＯＫ
うっうーん　いいんじゃなーい
M-hm, I think we're good.
うん
Yeah!
I looked cool, didn't I?!
俺カッコよかったろう？
“貴様に名乗る名前などない”
ってー
"We don't give out our names to people like you!"
That was awesome.
しびれるねぇ
はいはい
Yeah, yeah...
What kind of reaction is that?!
なんだよそのリアクション
How was I? I threw in some of my own lines.
私はどうだった？
アドリブ入れてみたんだが
You overdid it!
やりすぎだよ
"It's over. And you're through!" That makes no sense.
“これで終わりだ そして
ジ・エンドだ”って
意味わかんねぇだろ
Sorry. I'll refrain from improvising.
すまない　アドリブは慎むよ
で プレゼントは決まったの？
So did you decide on a present?
Nah, I took your advice and tried asking him
いやぁ　アドバイスどおり
ファッション系あたってみたけど
what sort of fashion he liked, but he didn't seem interested.
興味なしだった
I see... Sorry.
そっか　ごめん
It's all right. Thanks for helping.
いや
ありがとな
ああ
So I'm just going to go with this.
だから俺もこれで
What are you talking about? This is a present from all of us!
何言ってんの？　これは
私たちからのプレゼントなの
あんたはパートナーとして
特別にあげなきゃ
You need to give something special to your partner separately!
うーん
Thank you for doing this every year.
毎年ありがとうございます
It's no problem.
いいえ
As your maid, baking a cake
メイドとして今できる事と言ったら
is pretty much the only thing I can do for you.
ケーキを焼く事くらいですから
これからも誕生日には必ず
ケーキを送ってあげますからね
I'll continue to send you cakes for your birthday.
ありがとう　サマンサ
Thank you, Samantha!
うふふ
Master?
坊っちゃん
あっ すいません
Oh, sorry.
I'm sure that your parents are sending
きっと今頃 天国の旦那様と奥様も
祝福されてますよ
you their blessings from the heavens.
では良いお誕生日を
I wish you a happy birthday.
Thank you.
はい
もしもし
Hello?
Bad news! We've got a situation on our hands! Come right away!
大変だ 大事件なんだ
今すぐ来てくれ
あ あっ
はあ 異常なーし
Nothing out of the ordinary.
しっかし何度見てもスゲーな これ
This thing is really something. Six million Stern Dollars, huh?
600万ドルか
Nothing here, and nothing here!
異常なし　こちらも異常なーし
ああ？
Good evening.
こんばんは
うっ あっ
あっ あっ ああー
So, did you decide on a present?
で プレゼント何にしたの？
おお いろいろ考えたんだけど
Yeah! I thought of a lot of things
俺がプレゼントってことで
いいかなっと
and figured that I should be his present.
That's no good! He'd never like that.
絶対良くない
喜ぶわけないでしょ
Yeah, I guess not, huh?
ああ やっぱりそっか？
You should at least get him something.
とりあえずなんか準備しなきゃ
But we don't have any time.
いや でももう時間が
Here he comes.
来た来た来た
Hurry up and hide!
ほら早く隠れろ
Hey!
おう
What's this about a situation?
なんですか？　事件って
I called you because
お前を呼んだのは他でもない
there is a gang of thieves hiding around here.
どうやらこの辺に
窃盗団が潜んでいるらしいんだ
Shall we catch them together?
一緒に捕まえないか？
No, thank you.
お断りします
ああ？
Huh?
I thought it might be something like this.
どうせ そんな事じゃないかと
思いましたよ
You should only do that if we get a call from HQ.
そういうのは
本部の連絡があってから
ええいっ
A pickpocket!
スリだ！
ぬあっ
何やってんだよ
What are you doing?
引っかかっちゃってよ
It got stuck...
早く行けよ
Get going already.
Yeah, but...
だってよう
お知り合いの方ですか？
A friend of yours?
いや違う違う
No, not at all!
ええーい
Hey! That thief ran away!
あっ逃げやがったな窃盗団め
追いかけるのを手伝ってくれ
Help me catch him!
No.
嫌です
頼むから行こうぜ
Come on, let's go!
あーっと
ああっ
あーすいません
Oh, sorry.
もう何やってんの
Jeez. What is he doing?
Excuse me, but the thief is completely out of sight.
あの　完全に犯人見失ってますけど
え えっ？
What?
あ あっっあ
ふっふふふふーん
There's no way of finding him anymore.
もう見つかりませんて
That's not true!
そんなことない
Let's see... Where was it?
あれ どこだっけ
Where was what?
“どこだっけ”って何ですか？
逃げる場所知ってるんですか？
Do you know where he's run off to?
ええああ 違う違う
No! Not at all! He's probably around somewhere...
どこかに必ず
ああ！　見つけたぞ！
Ah! There he is!
おい！　お前だな
窃盗犯の親分は
Hey!
You're the boss of the thieves, aren't you?
How did you know?
なぜわかった？
なぜ？　ええ なぜって…
How? Umm, how?
He's improvising again.
コイツまた
アドリブ入れやがったな
Who are you guys?
貴様ら何者だ？
そう それだよそれ
Yes, that's what I want!
ぬーははっは
We don't give out our names to—
貴様に名乗る名前など
バーナビー
Barnaby.
Huh?
I'm Barnaby Brooks Jr. Have you heard of that name?
僕はバーナビー・ブルックスJr．
この名前に聞き覚えはないか？
You mean... the Hero?!
まさかヒーロー？
Give up and surrender yourself.
あきらめて投降しなさい
じゃ 僕はここで
Well, I'm done here.
え ええ？　なんで？
Huh? Why?
He wouldn't bother running from a Hero.
ヒーローを前にして逃げないでしょ？
Case closed.
もう解決じゃないですか？
ちょ 待てって
Hey, wait!
Haven't we done enough?!
もういいでしょ
Put your hands up!
手を挙げな
Oh no! We're surrounded.
ヤバい囲まれた
You've been badmouthing our boss—calling him scum.
うちの親ビンにひどい事
言ってくれるじゃないか
クズ野郎だなんて
No one ever said that.
そんな事誰も言ってませんけど
Huh?
え？
そうなの？
Really?
ええっと　どうしよ？
Umm, what should I do?
Are you making fun of me?!
お前ら僕の事
バカにしてんのか？
Oh, right! Save us!
あ そうだ　助けてくれぇ
ダメだ　死ね！
No. Die!
えっ？
はっ？
ん？　おっ
What's going on?
えっ どういう事？
That's what I want to know!
それはこっちのセリフですよ
You tried to use me as a shield, didn't you?!
あなた今
僕を盾にしようとしてましたね
Uh, well, never mind that.
いいや　そんな事よりも
Hey, why did a bullet come out just now?
今どうして弾 出たの？
Why are you talking to the thieves?
何で犯人に話しかけてるんですか？
What's going on here?
何だこれ？
Oh, this is...
ああ これは…
Master!
坊っちゃん
よくやった　逃げろ！
Nice work!
Get us out of here!
いいっ
Something's not right.
なーんか おかしいわね
Let's go.
行きましょ
What just happened?
何だったんだ今の？
だから こっちのセリフですよ
That's what I want to know! What's going on here?
一体これは どういう事ですか？
Ummm...
いやあ あの実は…
To tell you the truth,
バニーのバースデーサプライズを
we were going to throw you a surprise birthday party.
またおせっかいですか
More of your meddling! How many times do I have to tell you?
何度言ったらわかるんですか？
あなたは
えっ
You see how you always end up
結局こうやって
周りに迷惑かけてるんですよ
causing problems for those around you?!
おっ
ボンジュー　ヒーロー
Bonjour, Heroes!
Orders from the Justice Bureau. There's been a robbery.
地方局から通達よ
強盗事件発生
速やかに出動
Get to work right away!
H-Hey!
うう　お　おい
Here's HERO TV!
さあ始まりました
ヒーローＴＶ
さて今日の犯人は？
Now then...
Today's criminal is...
いました！　指名手配中の怪盗団
ポーリー一味だ
There they are!
It's the Pauly Gang, wanted for robbery!
A NEXT?
ＮＥＸＴ？
イエス
Yes!
ダイヤモンドで体を包み込む
能力らしいわ
He's able to cover his body in diamonds.
That sounds tough. What should we do, Lil' Bunny?
そりゃあ　固そうだな
どうする？　バニーちゃん？
Don't bother with me anymore!
もう僕に関わらないでください
Huh?
え？
Nothing good happens whenever you're involved.
あなたが関わるとロクなことがない
From now on, I'll handle things
これからはコンビだとは考えず
僕１人で何とかしますから
under the notion that we're not a team.
Tiger & Barnaby! You guys ready?!
準備はいいか？
タイガーアンドバーニー
You're pretty loud over the speaker.
マイク・トースト声がでかいな
Whoa!
おわっ
んーんっ
おおっ？
それは おまけだよ
That's an extra for you guys!
はっ？
Huh?
I heard it was Barnaby's birthday, so I modified the suit.
バーナビーが誕生日だと聞いて
スーツを改造しておいた
ついでにタイガーもな
And Tiger's too.
Huh?
え？　どこ？　えっ
Huh? Where? Hm? Huh? Ow ow ow...
ええ　痛ててて
なーんと最初に登場したのは
Whoa!
Sky High, the King of Heroes, is the first one on the scene!
キング オブ ヒーロー　スカイハイ
Our planned skit was ruined because of you.
君たちのせいで練習した芝居が
無駄になってしまったんだ
And I worked hard to remember my lines!
せっかく覚えたのに
ハーッ
スカーイハーイ
Sky High!
うわあっ
ええいっ
Let's go!
行くぞ
ふんっ　うん？
えっ へっ へっ
いっ へっ へっ
おっ！
なあっ
なーんと！　ここでタイガーと
バーナビーが能力を発動！
And we see Tiger and Barnaby activating their powers!
５分間のハンドレットパワー
開始です
They have five minutes to use their Hundred Power!
Scatter!
散らばれ
Huh?
うわああ
おっ？
Sky High has captured one of them!
スカイハイが捕獲だー！
I won't forgive you guys.
君たちは許さない
I'm sorry.
すみませーん
Let's get the next one, Bunny.
次行くぞバニー
えっ？　え？
バニー？
Huh?
Bunny?
はあっ
うわーっ
My ice is a little cold, but your crime—
私の氷はちょっぴりコールド
あなたの悪事を…
遅かったわ
I'm too late.
Hey! At least let me finish my catch phrase.
ちょっと！
決めゼリフくらい言わせてよ
Me too.
私だって
I also wanted to say my catch phrase.
決めゼリフが言いたかった
I was standing by that whole time.
ずっと待ってたのに
Alone, in a back alley...
路地裏で１人たたずむ私
It was very lonely.
とても さみしかった
To make up for it, I'll let you have the last one.
じゃあ お詫びで残りの犯人
譲ってあげるわ
捕まえてきたら？
Go catch him.
いや 遠慮しておくよ
No, I'll pass. Let's let them handle it.
ここは彼らに任せてみようじゃないか
ええ？
Huh?
After all, today is a special day.
だって今日は特別な日だろ？
ぬおおー
Damn bastard!
野郎！
You're mine now!
もう こっちのもんだ
どわっ　くっ
See you!
じゃあな
おっ
てやーっ
Stop it! Let me go!
やめろ！放せ！
You're not getting away!
逃がすかよ！
Powers exhausted in 30 seconds.
能力終了30秒前
Hey, this is bad!
おお ヤバい
もうすぐ能力が切れるぞ
Our powers are going to run out soon!
わかってますよ
I know that!
どうして わざわざ敵の前で
Why do you have to say that in front of the enemy?
So your powers are about to run out?
お前ら能力切れちゃうのか？
Then I'll play around with you guys one last time!
じゃ 最後に遊んでやるよ
なら お言葉に甘えて
Thanks for the offer!
Man, you're tough!
固っ
ひっひーん
フーッ
フフッ
なっ
あっ
No one can defeat me!
誰も僕には勝てないんだよ
Do something!
なんとかしなさいよ
Uh-oh! Not even Tiger and Barnaby's powers
なんと！
タイガーとバーナビーの力でも
seem to stand a chance against that diamond skin!
ダイアモンドの固さには
お手あげか？
いひっ　ヒーローでも無理なんだ
Even Heroes can't defeat me!
僕は世界一強いんだ
I'm the strongest person in the world!
Five seconds remaining...
５秒前
Four...
Three...
くっ
おお
Good Luck Mode!
Good Luck Mode
Three...
Two...
One...
ウオーーッ
Tiger & Bunny. Over and out!
TIGER ＆ BUNNY
OVER ＆ OUT
ああーっ　ああ
We did it.
やったあ
Good job, you two!
いいぞ　おふたりさん！
This feature is amazing! It boosts our power!
すごい機能ですね これ
パワーがアップするんだ
いや パワーは何も変わらない
No! Your power doesn't change at all.
えっ？
Huh?
It just makes you look cooler in battle.
それは戦闘を派手にするために
見た目をカッコ良くしただけだ
What? That's it?
うえ？　そうなの？
Then what about that power just now?
じゃあ今の力って？
It was the result of your splendid teamwork.
君たちの
素晴らしい連携プレーの賜物だ！
Huh?
はあ？
２人の力を同時に加えて
ダイヤモンドを砕くとはね
I never expected you two to smash through the diamond
with your combined powers.
We didn't really work together.
いやいや　別に連携なんて
勘違いしないでくださいよ
今のは偶然なんで…
Don't get the wrong idea. That was just a coincidence.
Oh, come on! You guys were completely in sync.
まったまたー
バッチリ息が合ってたぞ
ようやくコンビらしく
なってきたんじゃないか？
You're finally starting to act like a team.
おっ　えい
うわっ やられちゃう
あっ　お前にやるよ
You can have this one.
えっ？
It's a birthday present!
バースデープレゼントだ
はあ？
Excuse me?
まさかダイヤが欲しいって
本気にしてたんですか？
Don't tell me you took it seriously
when I said I wanted that diamond?
I could never accept it.
もらえるわけないでしょ
違う　こいつはお前が
捕まえたことにしろ
Not that! I'm letting you arrest him.
What?
はっ？
It's points that you want, right?
お前が欲しいのはポイントだろ？
ハッピーバースデー
Happy birthday.
ふっふーん
There's nothing happy about it.
別に喜びませんよ
えっ？
Huh?
“おせっかいはうんざりだ”って
言ったでしょ？
I told you that I'm sick of your meddling!
でも…
But...
何が“ハッピーバースデー”
ですか？
Happy birthday? How embarrassing.
恥ずかしい
うああ
Oh, is that so?
ああ そうかよう
Why are you smiling?
なんでニヤけてんの？
ニヤけてなんていません
I'm not smiling.
So, does this stay this way?
で これ戻んねぇの？
僕が消え 遠い未来で
boku ga kie tooi mirai de kaseki ni nattara
When I die and become a fossil in the far future,
化石になったら
人は僕に何を見るだろう
hito wa boku ni nani wo miru darou?
what will people see me as?
分析して 名を付けて
bunseki shite na wo tsukete kaidoku wo shitemo
They may try to analyze, name, and understand me,
解読をしても
愛した人は僕しか知らない
aishita hito wa boku shika shiranai
but only I will know the person I loved.
ハロー 生きること
HELLO ikiru koto
Hello, existence.
君の他に 君はできない
kimi no hoka ni kimi wa dekinai
Only you alone can live your life.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
僕らは何を感じられるだろう
bokura wa nani wo kanjirareru darou?
What can we feel from it?
奇跡は宇宙だけじゃないよ
kiseki wa uchuu dake janai yo
The universe isn't the only miracle.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
目を閉じたって 閉じきれないよ
me wo tojitatte tojikirenaiyo
You can try to shut your eyes, but you can't shut out your heart.
あの星さえ 持てなかった心
ano hoshi sae motenakatta kokoro
It's something that even the stars did not possess.
ほんと びっくりしたわよ
That really surprised me.
まさか本物の窃盗団と
かち合うとはな
I never thought we'd run into a real gang of robbers.
結局きっちり
お祝いできなかったね
In the end, we weren't able to throw a proper party!
あれ？　プレゼントのうさちゃん
どこやった？
Huh? What happened to that bunny we got as a present?
ああ　あれは確か
Oh, if I'm not mistaken...
別に怪しいもんじゃないって
I'm not anyone suspicious.
じゃあ これは何だ？
Then what's this?
ああ　それは友人の
Oh, that's for a friend.
怪しすぎる　こっち来い！
How suspicious! Come with me!
おおい　ちょっと
Hey! Wait!
はーい！
TIGER ＆ BUNNYの
好きなものは
後にとっておいて食べるほう
Hi! This is Barnaby, the member of "Tiger & Bunny"
バーナビーです
え？　ファイヤーエンブレムに
殺人容疑？
who saves his favorite food for last.
What? Fire Emblem is suspected of murder?
この紋章は？
次回　TIGER ＆ BUNNY
That mark!
Fire is good servant
but a bad master
Next time on TIGER & BUNNY:
See you
See you!